<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-01T21:16:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jason’s Seattle Blog</title><subtitle>Experiencing the Pacific Northwest</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meditation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/22/meditation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meditation" /><published>2018-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/22/meditation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/02/22/meditation.html">&lt;p&gt;Today I watched a hummingbird in the tree in front of my window. I was still, paying attention to my breath (inhale, exhale). The bird was perched on a narrow branch for so long that I began to question whether it was in fact a hummingbird. Then it took off, using the rotor-ish movement of its wings to fly motionless next to another branch. Eventually he flew away. This all lasted for a minute or two, it felt like a rather long time, but it probably wasn’t long at all. It did feel as though I was really inhabiting the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started meditating again a few months ago, shooting for  10 minutes of silent mindfulness every day. I have experimented with meditating at different times of the day and I now realize that while it doesn’t need to be the very first thing I do, if I wait until mid-day or later, my head is so full of “to-dos” and desires, that it’s very difficult to quiet my thoughts enough to sit still even for 5 minutes.  So now, I do it during breakfast (usually after going to the gym) while sipping my first coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My apartment is on a courtyard and the window in the kitchen is at the level of the main branches of four trees, American Hornbeams. The bare tree branches form interesting geometric patterns; if it is windy, they sway and if it is sunny, the tree’s shadows array themselves on the wall opposite. It makes for a meditative environment, though some days schedule dictates that my silent meditation take place elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many people who practice different forms of meditation, I am not so busy that it is a coping mechanism to get me through a hectic  day. Still there are times that I am overwhelmed still by my transition to life in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today I watched a hummingbird in the tree in front of my window. I was still, paying attention to my breath (inhale, exhale). The bird was perched on a narrow branch for so long that I began to question whether it was in fact a hummingbird. Then it took off, using the rotor-ish movement of its wings to fly motionless next to another branch. Eventually he flew away. This all lasted for a minute or two, it felt like a rather long time, but it probably wasn’t long at all. It did feel as though I was really inhabiting the moment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year Roadtrip</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/12/new-year-roadtrip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year Roadtrip" /><published>2018-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/12/new-year-roadtrip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/12/new-year-roadtrip.html">&lt;p&gt;I am marking the early part of the year by making an 8-day road trip from Seattle to Los Angeles and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s mind-blowing that we are only (still) in the second week of the year! The holiday ‘break’ already seems as though it was long ago. Early weeks of a year usually feel like a fresh, hopeful start: the hope being that this year it will be possible to make up for whatever the previous year was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love a road trip…seeing new scenery, the improvisational aspect of not knowing exactly where a day will start and end, stopping to see friends who live along the route and brief encounters with strangers in restaurants and coffee shops. This is my first trip down the length of the west coast: though my specific timing has meant sticking to the biggest interstate, I5, some of the scenery in the NW was spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also true that one of the purposes of the trip is to reintroduce myself to the sun a few months into my first PNW winter. After driving through rain in Washington and Oregon, the sun appeared almost immediately after crossing the state line into California. Staying one day in San Jose, I enjoyed a hike in sunny foothills of Cupertino with my friend, D. Am making another one-day stop (with hike) in Carmel to see another family friend. Then it’s on to LA and a (forecast) warm weekend down south.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am marking the early part of the year by making an 8-day road trip from Seattle to Los Angeles and back.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2017 in Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/30/year-in-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2017 in Review" /><published>2017-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/30/year-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/30/year-in-review.html">&lt;p&gt;2017 was a big year for me. After spending Q1 living with Jono on NYC’s UWS, I drove cross-country and transplanted myself to Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am proud to have accomplished a number of things during the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;disengaged from work and other familiar patterns of every day life in NYC and reestablished healthy daily habits in Seattle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spent significant time in Seattle building relationships, nurturing existing friendships, and acquainting myself with a few old friends I had not seen for a long time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Studied new technology throughout the year and, in particular, dove deeper into data science for the last 3 1/2 months. Data science has clicked with me like no other technology area. I believe it has helped me reach a new career frontier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did a decent amount of exploring throughout the year by driving cross-country, traveling to a few different parts of the PNW, on brief trips to California,  Nicaragua, and Martha’s Vineyard (my first visit to an island I have heard about for many years).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reconciled myself with divorce and stayed friendly with AM. At same time, built foundations of a new relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stayed in regular, close contact with my daughter and son, mainly via text messaging and social media, but also spent some nice phone and face-to-face time with each.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Found two nice places to live in Seattle: a serene, beautiful landing pad in Ballard and a well-located, aesthetic 1BR in Capitol Hill which enabled me to consolidate my belongings and feel as though I am at home here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a few things that didn’t go as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have not yet found full-time work in Seattle though it seems clear there are appropriate jobs out here. In past, networking has been enough to ‘land’ me something, but here it is not working.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Related to no full-time work: too much anxiety. I have not been able to “trust the process” and accept that it will take a while. The meditation and exercise have helped in this area.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Related to anxiety: I over-ate and gained pounds despite exercising actively throughout the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These last few items provide areas to focus and improve in 2018. Am still considering whether, aside from remediating these areas, I wish to make any special resolution for the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">2017 was a big year for me. After spending Q1 living with Jono on NYC’s UWS, I drove cross-country and transplanted myself to Seattle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seattle Myths Pt 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/18/seattle-myths_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seattle Myths Pt 1" /><published>2017-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/18/seattle-myths_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/18/seattle-myths_1.html">&lt;p&gt;I have noticed there are  a few little white lies that Seattlites tell each other about their city.  Prominent on the list, “Sure it rains here, but it really doesn’t rain hard. Everyone goes outside and no one uses an umbrella.”  The last bit, about umbrellas, is true, but it’s a stupid thing to say because, actually, it often rains really hard.  I live a ten minute walk away from my gym and in the last month there have been at least 5 days on which I had to wear boots or other waterproof shoes instead of going in my ‘trainers.’  So if you are going to come to Seattle, be prepared for at least some hard rain!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have noticed there are a few little white lies that Seattlites tell each other about their city. Prominent on the list, “Sure it rains here, but it really doesn’t rain hard. Everyone goes outside and no one uses an umbrella.” The last bit, about umbrellas, is true, but it’s a stupid thing to say because, actually, it often rains really hard. I live a ten minute walk away from my gym and in the last month there have been at least 5 days on which I had to wear boots or other waterproof shoes instead of going in my ‘trainers.’ So if you are going to come to Seattle, be prepared for at least some hard rain!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CFSBK Dreams</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/cfsbk-dreams.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CFSBK Dreams" /><published>2017-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/cfsbk-dreams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/27/cfsbk-dreams.html">&lt;p&gt;When I walked into 597 Degraw in fall 2010, I was totally unsuspecting. I knew after my first three classes (with Margie, Fox and David) that the coaches were mindful, uncompromising about form, and generally all about doing everything the right way. Yep, it was a good gym!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only with time, did I come to understand what an engaging, crazy-fun but serious-about-fitness community CFSBK is.  When I think about the gym, I think about Community Potlucks, Crash-B rowing programs, Strength Cycle, volunteering for Iron Maidens, and running workouts at Red Hook. As a front desk staffer, I loved getting to know every member by name. I will never forget one of my first front desk shifts during a January blizzard that shut down the subway. Typically, CFSBK was open and David, after telling other coaches to stay home, manned the fort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think about how and where I would live if I ever moved back to Brooklyn. In every version of my daydream, I always live walking distance from CFSBK and the gym is always a central part of my imagined new life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I walked into 597 Degraw in fall 2010, I was totally unsuspecting. I knew after my first three classes (with Margie, Fox and David) that the coaches were mindful, uncompromising about form, and generally all about doing everything the right way. Yep, it was a good gym!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Science</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/data-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Science" /><published>2017-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/data-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/data-science.html">&lt;p&gt;I recently started a online continuing-ed program in data science. Previously, I had done a significant portion of a similar program in web development. I considered completing that program, which would require less time and lead to potentially equally as many employment opportunities. For a number of reasons, figuring out data seems very important and compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max unintentionally articulated the reason why when I described to him the structure of the program and the nature of the first assignment. We were talking about the difference between learning a technology like Python for data science vs. learning the same tool for software engineering. He said, software engineers don’t have to explain why they are taking a certain approach to an end user, but a data scientist is always seeking to explain her findings in plain English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My motivations about technology - in all my professional and personal roles - are similarly much more about explaining or applying technology to “real life.”  I realized that I am not, as many of my friends with engineering education are, all about building things or finding a better way to do x (thought I have a bit of that too). For me, data science is not only about making myself more appealing on the contemporary job market, but potentially can facilitate longer term goals about research and/or writing projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently started a online continuing-ed program in data science. Previously, I had done a significant portion of a similar program in web development. I considered completing that program, which would require less time and lead to potentially equally as many employment opportunities. For a number of reasons, figuring out data seems very important and compelling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Misc Seattle Thoughts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/19/misc-seattle_thoughts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Misc Seattle Thoughts" /><published>2017-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/19/misc-seattle_thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/19/misc-seattle_thoughts.html">&lt;p&gt;BTW - WSJ app for both iPhone and iPad recently improved greatly.  It is good an experience as NYT app and almost as good as the actual paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started reading the Seattle Times online. Not a very good paper overall, but the coverage of state and regional issues is pretty important to me now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While up at Monika’s house on Samish island, I visited the city of Bellingham just 45 miles south of Vancouver, BC.  Very nice and pretty medium-sized city with a big university (Western Washington).  From Bellingham, there is weekly (biweekly in summer) ferry service to Alaska.  The Canadians drive down to go to CostCo and TJs in Bellingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the salmon are spawning. At the Ballard locks they have a fish ladder that allows the salmon to migrate from the sea to Lake Washington (and beyond to their spawning grounds). There is a viewing area from which you can see the big salmon swimming against the current.  Nature is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">BTW - WSJ app for both iPhone and iPad recently improved greatly. It is good an experience as NYT app and almost as good as the actual paper.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Practice: First Things</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/fresh-mind.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Practice: First Things" /><published>2017-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/fresh-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/fresh-mind.html">&lt;p&gt;Am getting better at understanding that certain things only get done if they are approached with a fresh, rested mind. Creating a new resume draft or a document for a headhunter is a little dry, requires a sales mindset, and generally will not get accomplished if it is the seventh or eighth item on my daily to-do list. Some other items like daily foreign language practice or 10 minutes of meditation are easier to squeeze in later, but truthfully are sloppier if they are done later in the day. Have been leaving coding practice to the evening and, as a result, have been doing relatively little of it. Early morning exercise is not easy for me, but I recognize that if I do my CrossFit at 9am, it has been conquered. If I leave it to the evening, it’s more of a 50/50 thing. However, later in the day, sitting at my desk, I am tired.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Am getting better at understanding that certain things only get done if they are approached with a fresh, rested mind. Creating a new resume draft or a document for a headhunter is a little dry, requires a sales mindset, and generally will not get accomplished if it is the seventh or eighth item on my daily to-do list. Some other items like daily foreign language practice or 10 minutes of meditation are easier to squeeze in later, but truthfully are sloppier if they are done later in the day. Have been leaving coding practice to the evening and, as a result, have been doing relatively little of it. Early morning exercise is not easy for me, but I recognize that if I do my CrossFit at 9am, it has been conquered. If I leave it to the evening, it’s more of a 50/50 thing. However, later in the day, sitting at my desk, I am tired.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Honesty and “the Process?”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/13/the_process.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Honesty and &quot;the Process?&quot;" /><published>2017-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/13/the_process</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/13/the_process.html">&lt;p&gt;One struggle I have with this kind of writing is how truthful to be.  It’s easy to write a post where the qualities or activities are described in a positive light. There are plenty of times when my self-assessment is  darker: where I believe I have been ineffective, lazy or bad in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that upon reflection or discussion with a confidant, you realize that these bad times are part of “the process” and were necessary. But, to be perfectly honest, there are times when we all fail to meet expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m definitely feeling that way at the moment.  Any momentum I had going back in late June dried up over the July 4th holiday. I’m starting to question how long it will take me to start generating meetings with consequential people that I would like to have in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this just part of “the process”?&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;“The process” is a reference to the long-slow rebuild undertaken by the Philadelphia 76ers under GM Sam Hinkie. Hinkie was fired from his job two years into “the process” even though the team is recognized as a rising power in the NBA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One struggle I have with this kind of writing is how truthful to be. It’s easy to write a post where the qualities or activities are described in a positive light. There are plenty of times when my self-assessment is darker: where I believe I have been ineffective, lazy or bad in some way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Sell is Human: Six Successors to the Elevator Pitch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/22/new_elevator_pitch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Sell is Human: Six Successors to the Elevator Pitch" /><published>2017-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/22/new_elevator_pitch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/22/new_elevator_pitch.html">&lt;p&gt;This week I read Daniel Pink - To Sell is Human: The Surprising Truth About Moving Others. Pink is one of the most popular writers about business today and the thesis of the book that in the post-industrial economy, sales skills have become important in a great many (perhaps even the majority of) occupations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book makes a number of good points about selling skills, enumerating what they are, and suggesting ways anyone who is not in a traditional selling role can cultivate those skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion the pithiest and best part in his chapter on the
“6 Successors to the Elevator Pitch”  which actually updates the concept of “elevator pitch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The six successor pitches are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One word pitch. eg. “search”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Question pitch (eg. “are you better off now than you sere four years ago?”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhyming pitch (“If it doesn’t fit, you must acquit.”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subject-line pitch( i.e., how do you get people to read an email)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twitter pitch (140 characters or fewer).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pixar Pitch (the archetypal storyline of an animated film). Once about a time &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Every day, &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. One day, &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Because of that,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;em&gt;. Until finally __&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;__ .  See Emma Coats’s story rules on the Pixar pitch - http://www.pixartouchbook.com/blog/2011/5/15/pixar-story-rules-one-version.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this to be a very insightful framework - certainly food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week I read Daniel Pink - To Sell is Human: The Surprising Truth About Moving Others. Pink is one of the most popular writers about business today and the thesis of the book that in the post-industrial economy, sales skills have become important in a great many (perhaps even the majority of) occupations.</summary></entry></feed>